A Guide to the Virginia Volunteers, Muster-In Rolls, 1884-1919
Library of Virginia
Volume XVI: Muster-In Rolls, 1900, contains muster rolls for the following units: Richmond Grays; Co. B, 70th Regiment; Guard of the Commonwealth; Monticello Guard; Lynchburg Home Guard; Co. F; Alexandria Light Infantry; Co. H, 70th Regiment; Farmville Guard; West Augusta Guard; Washington Guards; Danville Light Infantry; Lee Rifles; Norfolk City Guard; Huntington Rifles; Peninsula Guards; Jackson Light Infantry; Suffolk Grays Infantry; Newport News Light Infantry; Co. H; Co. I; Portsmouth Rifle Co.; Old Dominion Guard of Portsmouth; Greensville Guards; Field Staff, & Band, Richmond Light Infantry Blues; Companies "A" & "B", Richmond Light Infantry Blues; Roanoke Light Infantry; Roanoke Blues; Piedmont Rifles; Hoge-Tyler Rifles of Pulaski; Clifton Forge Rifles; Staunton Rifles; Field & Staff, 1st Battalion Artillery; Batteries "A" through "C", 1st Battalion Artillery; Troop B Cavalry; Staff, 1st Naval Battalion; and Divisions "A" through "D", 1st Naval Battalion.
Volume XVII: Muster-In Rolls, 1901, contains muster rolls for the following units: Field, Staff, & Band, 70th Regiment Infantry; Companies "A" through "M", 70th Regt.; Field, Staff, & Band, 71st Regiment Infantry; Companies "A" through "M", 71st Regt; Field, Staff, & Band, 1st Battalion Artillery; Batteries "A" through "C", 1st Battalion Artillery; and Troop B Cavalry. The musters also include the following unattached infantry companies: Field, Staff, & Band, Richmond Light Infantry Blues; Companies "A" & "B", Richmond Light Infantry Blues; Roanoke Light Infantry; Roanoke Blues; Piedmont Rifles; Hoge-Tyler Rifles of Pulaski; Clifton Forge Rifles; and the Staunton Rifles.
Volume XVIII: Muster-In Rolls, 1902, contains muster rolls for the following units: Field, Staff, & Band, 70th Regiment Infantry; Companies "A" through "M", 70th Regt.; Field, Staff, & Band, 71st Regiment Infantry; Companies "A" through "M", 71st Regt; Field, Staff, & Band, 1st Battalion Artillery; Batteries "A" through "C", 1st Battalion Artillery; and Troop B Cavalry. The musters also include the following unattached infantry companies: Field, Staff, & Band, Richmond Light Infantry Blues; Companies "A" & "B", Richmond Light Infantry Blues; Staunton Rifles; Hoge-Tyler Rifles of Pulaski; Clifton Forge Rifles; Culpeper Minute Men; Roanoke Light Infantry; Roanoke Blues; and the Page Riflemen.
Volume XIX: Muster-In Rolls, 1903-1904, contains muster rolls for the following units: Field, Staff, & Band, 70th Regiment Infantry; Companies "A" through "M", 70th Regt.; Field, Staff, & Band, 71st Regiment Infantry; Companies "A" through "M", 71st Regt; Field, Staff, & Band, 1st Battalion Artillery; Batteries "A" through "C", 1st Battalion Artillery; and Troop B Cavalry. The musters also include the following unattached infantry companies: Roanoke Blues; Mecklenburg Guard; Petersburg Grays; Staunton Rifles; Clifton Forge Rifles; Page Riflemen; Culpeper Minute Men; Roanoke Light Infantry; Field, Staff, & Band, Richmond Light Infantry Blues; Companies "A" & "B", Richmond Light Infantry Blues; and the Warren Light Infantry. Volume XX: Muster-In Rolls, 1904-1905, contains muster rolls for the following units: Field, Staff, & Band, 70th Regiment Infantry; Companies "A" through "M", 70th Regt.; Field, Staff, & Band, 71st Regiment Infantry; Companies "A" through "M", 71st Regt; Field, Staff, & Band, 1st Battalion Artillery; Batteries "A" through "C", 1st Battalion Artillery; and Troop B Cavalry. The musters also include the following unattached infantry companies: Field, Staff, & Band, Richmond Light Infantry Blues; Companies "A" & "B", Richmond Light Infantry Blues; Clifton Forge Rifles; Staunton Rifles; Page Riflemen; Culpeper Minute Men; Warren Light Infantry; Petersburg Grays; Mecklenburg Guard; Roanoke Light Infantry; and the Roanoke Blues.
Volume XXI: Muster-In Rolls, 1905-1906, contains muster rolls for the following units: Field, Staff, & Band, 70th Regiment Infantry; Companies "A" through "M", 70th Regt.; Field, Staff, & Band, 71st Regiment Infantry; Companies "A" through "M", 71st Regt; Field, Staff, & Band, 1st Battalion Artillery; Field, Staff, & Band, 72nd Regiment Infantry; Companies "A" through "H", 72nd Regt.; and Batteries "A" through "C", 1st Battalion Artillery (Battery C disbanded on March 28, 1905).
Volume XXII: Muster-In Rolls, 1906-1907, contains muster rolls for the following units of the Virginia Volunteers are included: Field, Staff, & Band, 70th Regiment Infantry; Companies "A" through "M", 70th Regt.; Field, Staff, & Band, 71st Regiment Infantry; Companies "A" through "M", 71st Regt.; Field, Staff, & Band, 1st Battalion Artillery; Field, Staff, & Band, 72nd Regiment Infantry; Companies "A" through "H", 72nd Regt.; Field, Staff, & Band, Richmond Light Infantry Blues; Companies "A" through "C", Richmond Light Infantry Blues (Company C was organized on March 30, 1907); and Batteries "A" through "C", 1st Battalion Artillery (Battery C disbanded on March 28, 1905 and reorganized on February 27, 1906).
Volume XXIII: Muster-In Rolls, 1907-1908, contains muster rolls for the following units: General & Staff, 1st Brigade; Companies "A" through "G", "I" through "M", 70th Regiment Infantry (Company H disbanded on January 30, 1907); Field, Staff, & Band, 71st Regiment Infantry; Companies "A" through "F", "H" through "M", 71st Regt. (Companies G & H disbanded on September 22, 1906); Field, Staff, & Band, 72nd Regiment Infantry; Companies "A" through "H", 72nd Regt.; Field, Staff, & Band, Richmond Light Infantry Blues; Companies "A" through "C", Richmond Light Infantry Blues (Company C was organized on March 30, 1907); Field, Staff, & Band, 1st Battalion Artillery; and Batteries "A" through "C", 1st Battalion Artillery (Battery C disbanded on March 28, 1905 and reorganized on February 27, 1906).
Volume XXIV: Muster-In Rolls, 1908-1909, contains muster rolls for the following units: General & Staff, 1st Brigade; Field, Staff, & Band, 70th Regiment (Became the 1st Regiment Infantry); Companies "A" through "G", "I" through "M", 1st Regiment Infantry (Company H disbanded on January 30, 1907); Field, Staff, & Band, 2nd Regiment Infantry; Companies "A" through "H", 2nd Regt. Infantry; Field, Staff, & Band, 4th Regiment Infantry; Companies "A" through "C", "E" & "F", and "K" through "M", 4th Regt. Infantry; Field, Staff, & Band, Richmond Light Infantry Blues; Companies "A" through "C", Richmond Light Infantry Blues; Field, Staff, & Band, 1st Battalion Artillery; Batteries "A" through "C", 1st Battalion Artillery; and the 1st through 3rd Companies of Coast Artillery.
Volume XXV: Muster-In Rolls, 1909-1910, contains muster rolls for the following units: Field, Staff, & Band, 70th Regiment (Became the 1st Regiment Infantry); Companies "A" through "G", "I" through "M", 1st Regiment Infantry (Company H disbanded on January 30, 1907); Field, Staff, & Band, 2nd Regiment Infantry; Companies "A" through "H", 2nd Regt. Infantry; Field, Staff, & Band, 4th Regiment Infantry; Companies "A" through "C", "E" & "F", and "K" through "M", 4th Regt. Infantry; Field, Staff, & Band, Richmond Light Infantry Blues; Companies "A" through "C", Richmond Light Infantry Blues; Field, Staff, & Band, 1st Battalion Artillery; Batteries "A" through "C", 1st Battalion Artillery; and the 1st through 4th Companies of Coast Artillery.
Volume XXVI: Muster-In Rolls, 1910, contains muster rolls for the following units: Staff Corps; Medical Corps; General & Staff, 1st Brigade; Field, Staff, & Band, 1st Regiment Infantry; Companies "A" through "M", 1st Regt. Infantry; Field, Staff, & Band, 2nd Regiment Infantry; Companies "A" through "H", 2nd Regt. Infantry; Field, Staff, & Band, 4th Regiment Infantry; Companies "A" through "C", "E" & "F", and "K" through "M", 4th Regt. Infantry; Field, Staff, & Band, Richmond Light Infantry Blues Battalion; Companies "A" through "D", Richmond Light Infantry Blues; Field, Staff, & Band, 1st Battalion Field Artillery; Batteries "A" through "C", 1st Battalion Field Artillery; and the 1st through 4th Companies of Coast Artillery.
Volume XXVII: Muster-In Rolls, 1911, contains muster rolls for the following units: General & Staff, 1st Brigade; Sanitary Troops, 1st Regiment Infantry; Field, Staff, & Band, 1st Regiment Infantry; Companies "A" through "M", 1st Regt. Infantry; Field, Staff, & Band, 2nd Regiment Infantry; Companies "A" through "H", 2nd Regt. Infantry; Field, Staff, & Band, 4th Regiment Infantry; Companies "A" through "C", "E" & "F", and "K" through "M", 4th Regt. Infantry; Field, Staff, & Band, Richmond Light Infantry Blues; Companies "A" through "D", Richmond Light Infantry Blues; Field, Staff, & Band, 1st Battalion Field Artillery; and Batteries "A" through "C", 1st Battalion Field Artillery.
Volume XXVIII: Muster-In Rolls, 1912, contains muster rolls for the following units: General & Staff, 1st Brigade; Field, Staff, & Band, 1st Regiment Infantry; Companies "A" through "M", 1st Regt. Infantry; Field, Staff, & Band, 2nd Regiment Infantry; Companies "A" through "K", 2nd Regt. Infantry; Field, Staff, & Band, 4th Regiment Infantry; Companies "A" through "G" & "K" through "M", 4th Regt. Infantry; Field, Staff, & Band, Richmond Light Infantry Blues; Companies "A" through "D", Richmond Light Infantry Blues; Field, Staff, & Band, 1st Battalion Field Artillery; and Batteries "A" through "C", 1st Battalion Field Artillery; Sanitary Troops, 4th Regiment Infantry; and Signal Corps.
Volume XXIX: Muster-In Rolls, 1913, contains muster rolls for the following units: General & Staff, 1st Brigade; Field, Staff, & Band, 1st Regiment Infantry; Companies "A" through "M", 1st Regt. Infantry; Field, Staff, & Band, 2nd Regiment Infantry; Companies "A" through "M", 2nd Regt. Infantry; Field, Staff, & Band, 4th Regiment Infantry; Companies "A" through "M", 4th Regt. Infantry; Field, Staff, & Band, Richmond Light Infantry Blues; Companies "A" through "D", Richmond Light Infantry Blues; Field, Staff, & Band, 1st Battalion Field Artillery; and Batteries "A" through "C", 1st Battalion Field Artillery; Staff & Medical Corps; Sanitary Troops, 1st Regiment Infantry; Medical Corps, 4th Regt. Infantry; Medical Corps, 2nd Regt. Infantry; and Type "C" Signal Corps.
Volume XXX: Muster-In Rolls, 1914, contains muster rolls for the following units: Field, Staff, & Band, 1st Battalion Field Artillery; and Batteries "A" through "C", 1st Battalion Field Artillery; Field, Staff, & Band, 1st Regiment Infantry; Companies "A" through "M", 1st Regt. Infantry; Field, Staff, & Band, 2nd Regiment Infantry; Companies "A" through "M", 2nd Regt. Infantry; Field, Staff, & Band, 4th Regiment Infantry; Companies "A" through "M", 4th Regt. Infantry; Hospital Corps, 1st Regiment Infantry; Sanitary Troops, 2nd Regiment Infantry; Sanitary Troops, 4th Regiment Infantry; Field, Staff, & Band, Richmond Light Infantry Blues; Companies "A" through "D", Richmond Light Infantry Blues; and Type "D" Signal Corps.
Volume XXXI: Muster-In Rolls, 1915, contains muster rolls for the following units of the Virginia Volunteers are included: Field, Staff, & Band, 1st Regiment Infantry; Hospital Corps, 1st Regt. Infantry; Companies "A" through "M", 1st Regt. Infantry; Field, Staff, & Band, 2nd Regiment Infantry; Hospital Corps, 2nd Regt. Infantry; Companies "A" through "M", 2nd Regt. Infantry; Field, Staff, & Band, 4th Regiment Infantry; Sanitary Troops, 4th Regiment Infantry; Companies "A" through "M", 4th Regt. Infantry; Field, Staff, & Band, Richmond Light Infantry Blues; Companies "A" through "D", Richmond Light Infantry Blues; Field, Staff, & Band, 1st Battalion Field Artillery; and Batteries "A" through "C", 1st Battalion Field Artillery; Signal Corps Detachmnet (Portsmouth); Type "D" Signal Corps; and Company A Field Hospital.
Volume XXXII: Muster-In Rolls, 1917-1918, contains muster rolls for the following units: Field, Staff, & Band, Richmond Light Infantry Blues Battalion; Companies "A" through "D", Richmond Light Infantry Blues Battalion; Field, Staff, & Band, Jo Lane Stern Battalion; Companies "A" through "D", Jo Lane Stern Battalion; Field, Staff, & Band of the Staff Corps & Departments; Albemarle Rifles; Allegheny Rifles; Bath Rifles; Berryville Guards; Blue Ridge Guard; Blue Ridge Rifles; Buckingham Guards; Clinch Valley Rifles; Colonial Rifles; Hanover Grays; Henry Guard; A.P. Hill Rifles; Hopewell Rifles; Lynchburg Home Guard; Lynchburg State Guard; Peaks of Otter Rifles; Petersburg Guards; Radford Home Guard; 1st & 2nd Companies Richmond Grays; Richmond Howitzers; Russell Guards; Tazewell Guards; Valley Riflemen; Washington Rifles; and Winchester State Guard.
Volume XXXIII: Muster-In Rolls, 1919, contains muster rolls for the following units: Field, Staff, & Band, Richmond Light Infantry Blues Battalion; Companies "A" through "D", Richmond Light Infantry Blues Battalion; Field, Staff, & Band, Jo Lane Stern Battalion; Companies "A" through "D", Jo Lane Stern Battalion; Bath Rifles; Berryville Guards; Buckingham Guards; Clinch Valley Rifles; Colonial Rifles; A.P. Hill Rifles; Lynchburg Home Guard; Peaks of Otter Rifles; Petersburg Guards; Radford Home Guard; 1st Company Richmond Grays; Valley Riflemen; Washington Rifles; and Winchester State Guard.
Arrangement
Arranged chronologically by volume.
Contents List
- Muster-In Rolls
  - Volume I, 1884
  - Volume II, 1885
  - Volume III, 1886
  - Volume IV, 1887
  - Volume V, 1888
  - Volume VI, 1889
  - Volume VII, 1890
  - Volume VIII, 1891
  - Volume IX, 1892
  - Volume X, 1893
  - Volume XI, 1894
  - Volume XII, 1895
  - Volume XIII, 1896
  - Volume XIV, 1897
  - Volume XV, 1898-1900
  - Volume XVI, 1900
  - Volume XVII, 1901
  - Volume XVIII, 1902
  - Volume XIX, 1903-1904
  - Volume XX, 1904-1905
  - Volume XXI, 1905-1906
  - Volume XXII, 1906-1907
  - Volume XXIII, 1907-1908
  - Volume XXIV, 1908-1909
  - Volume XXV, 1909-1910
  - Volume XXVI, 1910
  - Volume XXVII, 1911
  - Volume XXVIII, 1912
  - Volume XXIX, 1913
  - Volume XXX, 1914
  - Volume XXXI, 1915
  - Volume XXXII, 1917-1918
  - Volume XXXIII, 1919